# **Declan Kramper**

Product minded engineer seeking challenges

Chicago, IL

declankramper@gmail.com (630) 487-9527 <u>LinkedIn</u> <u>Portfolio</u>

# **Summary of Qualifications**

Digital Product Manager with 2+ years of success building transformative consumer-facing solutions across the retail and financial services industries. Known for ability to navigate ambiguity, think systemically, and leverage technical and interpersonal strengths to deliver business outcomes that exceed user expectations.

# **Work Experience**

## Associate Product Manager L2 | Publicis Sapient | Chicago, IL | 06/2022 - Current

- First individual in cohort to receive first and second promotions
- Led a 12-person cross-functional team to provide end-to-end support of new software development for an eCommerce client, excelling in a role three levels higher
- Shipped 27 new features in the first 15 months, strategically aimed at improving UX for their customers and empowering client teams to execute an ambitious product roadmap
- Achieved highest usability score across the entire website for the locations page redesign, reflecting a strong focus on user experience and functionality while differentiating solution from competitor
- Devised technical architecture and customer support workflow to fix store data issues, lowering customer support calls and reducing client's swivel chair efforts
- Spearheaded development scalable design system for a website seeing 400k sessions per week, enhancing the site's maintainability and configurability
- Presented live new feature demos to client Vice Presidents and business stakeholders every sprint
- Received high praise from clients: "Declan was self-motivated to get to an outcome, which is perhaps the GREATEST skill..." and "Given he is a self-starter, we often just counted on him figuring things out (which he did.)"
- Building generative AI applications on the firm's most critical project, which will be fundamental to future client offerings across the financial services and media landscape

## Field Engineer Intern | Renewable Energy Services | Broomfield, CO | 05/2021 - 08/2021

- Developed an excel VBA that translated units of labor and progress metrics into dollars and days to optimize production and reduce project cost, designed by talking with potential users

#### Business Owner | Next Level Lawn Service | Downers Grove, IL | 01/2013 - 01/2020

- Optimized business operations to increase revenue 438% throughout ownership
- Delivered exceptional customer care to 20+ clients weekly, creating life-long friendships

#### **Relevant Skills**

Data Analysis	Customer	Scaled-Agile	<b>User-Centered</b>	Technical	Roadmap	SQL &
	Insights	Certified	Design	Documentation	Prioritization	Programming

#### **Education**

## B.S. Mechanical Engineering - Purdue University | West Lafayette, IN | 05/2022

- Minor in Business Economics
- Achieved top marks in graduate-level Product and Process Design Thinking course
- Three-year recipient of the Mechanical Engineering Department Achievement Scholarship
- Served on executive committee of a national award-winning philanthropy

#### **Hobbies and Interests**

Last read: Last listen: Last race: Last build:
Thinking, Fast and Slow In Good Company Indianapolis Marathon Race Time Predictor App